Guide to the Louis Agassiz Fuertes papers, 1892-1954
Fuertes, Louis Agassiz papers,
- Photographic Materials (Box 25-29, 31, 36-38, 46-61, 112-113, 115-117, 129-130)
  - Photographs and 35mm slides (Box 25-27, 29, 31, 46-61, 112-113, 115-117, 129-130)
    - First ski club of Ithaca, 1890-1938; 1 photograph, 1 letter (Box 27, Folder 67)
      1938 letter from Charles Blair describing membership in A.S.E. at Ithaca High School and 1890 photograph mounted on cardstock of possible first ski club in US. Fuertes is a member.
      Fuertes, Louis Agassiz
      Whitaker, Robert K.
      Blair, Charles H., Jr.
      Williams, Timothy Shaler
    - Photographs of artwork: snipe and mallard duck, 21.5 x 28 cm and smaller; 3 photographs (Box 27, Folder 68)
      Inkjet prints
    - Modern photographs of Fuertes drawings (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Fuertes studio, 27.6 x 35 cm and smaller; 3 photographs (Box 31, Folder 1)
      Artists' studios
    - Fuertes and party at North Indian Field, St. John's Marshes, west of Melbourne, Florida, 1898; 27.4 x 35 cm (Box 31, Folder 2)
      Letter listing members of party and describing trip accompanies photograph.
      Fuertes, Louis Agassiz, 1874-1927
      Thayer, Abbott Handerson, 1849-1921
      Knight, Charles Robert, 1874-1953
      Hadley, Alden H.
      Thayer, Gerald
    - Photographs of artwork, 1990; 20.3 x 25.4 cm (Box 46-61)
    - Slides of artwork, 1990; 35 mm (Box 112)
    - Slides of artwork, 1990; 35 mm (Box 113)
    - Photographs of artwork on CDs, 2000 (Box 115)
    - Photograph of Abbott Thayer's children with Louis Agassiz Fuertes, 1900; 8.5 x 12.2 cm (Box 116)
      Related to photograph in Box 25, folder 7.
    - Photographs from Alaska, Mexico, Florida Keys and Columbia Expeditions, Printed later; 37.4 x 45 cm; 8 photographs; Toned. Mounted on board, captions inscriped in pencil on edge (recto). (Box 117)
      Mexico
    - A Souvenir of the Harriman Alaska Expedition, May - August 1899, Volume 1 New York to Cook Inlet, 1899; Harriman, Edward Henry, 1848-1909; Curtis, Edward S., 1868-1952; Merriam, C. Hart (Clinton Hart), 1855-1942; 144 photographs; Album with platinum-toned photographs mounted on pages. Photographs are identified. Includes map. (Box 129)
    - A Souvenir of the Harriman Alaska Expedition, Volume 2 Cook Inlet to Bering Strait and the Return Voyage, 1899; Harriman, Edward Henry, 1848-1909; Curtis, Edward S., 1868-1952; Merriam, C. Hart (Clinton Hart), 1855-1942; 111 photographs; Album with platinum-toned photographs mounted on pages. Photographs are identified. (Box 130)
  - Negatives (Box 27-29, 36-38)
    - Negatives of pages from letters from L.A.F. which contain sketches, 11 x 12.5 cm; 18 negatives (Box 27, Folder 61-63)
      Negatives (photographs)
    - Copy negatives of notebook pages, 18 x 13.5 cm; 15 negatives (Box 27, Folder 64-65)
    - Sharp-shinned hawk, Red tailed hawk, and turkeys, 1895-05-03; 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
    - Scarborough, NY, 1898-02; 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Scarborough, New York
    - Trip to Merritt Island, 1898-03; 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Merritt Island, Florida
    - Indian Field, St. John's Marshes, San Grass Lake, May-August; 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 6-10)
    - Alaska, 1899; 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 11)
      Relate to photographic prints in Box 26, folder 35-40.
    - Harriman, Alaska Expedition, 1899; 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 12-22)
    - Bahama Islands, 1902-04-24-1902-05-22; 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 23-29)
      Prints in Box 26, Folders 7-10 relate to negatives in these envelopes. Prints in Box 25, folder 15 match negatives in folders 26 and 28. Prints in Box 27, folder 59 relate to negatives in folder 28-29.
    - Bahamas, 1917; 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 30)
      Relate to prints in Box 27, folder 59.
    - With Thayers in Florida, 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 31-33)
    - Hunter's Lake Trip, 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Turkeys, 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 35-36)
      Turkeys
    - Indian Field (Purple Gallinula, Yellow Crested Alight Herons), 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous negatives, 9.4 x 9 cm (Box 28, Folder 38-45)
      Prints in Box 27, folder 59 relate to negatives in folders 39-41 and 45.
    - Fallen Leaf Lake, Glen Alpine, 13 x 10 cm; Positive print on glass plate (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Pyramid Peak in Summer, 13 x 10 cm; Positive print on glass plate (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Pyramid Peak in Winter, 13 x 10 cm; Positive print on glass plate (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Copy negatives of artwork, 4 x 5 cm (Box 36)
      001-298
    - Copy negatives of artwork, 4 x 5 cm (Box 37)
      300-498
    - Copy negatives of artwork, 4 x 5 cm (Box 38)
      500-920
- Series VII. Artwork
  - Arranged by Rare and Manuscript Numbers (by species/region)
    - The Louis Agassiz Fuertes Ornithological Artwork database is a searchable database of 2500 ornithological illustrations by Fuertes. Each piece is identified by a unique number. If a page has a drawing on both sides, each side has a number. The number is composed of three parts: 2662 XXX YYYZ 2662 = the collection number (this stays the same) XXX = species YYY = item number, Z = side of page Guide to Species: 001-768 American Ornithologists' Union Number for North American Birds 790 Bird Parts 800 South American Birds 810 African Birds 820 Asian Birds 830 European Birds 840 Middle Eastern Birds 850 Other Regions 900 Mammals 910 Amphibians, Reptiles, Insects, etc. 920 Landscapes and other
      Artworks with RMC numbers are arranged in boxes starting with the species number (XXX as shown above) and listed in ranges by those numbers. You can search by species if you know it's AOU number or region but items can also be found using the database above and looking for the ID Number given for an image. For instance all the images with an RMC number 2662-014-YYYZ would be in Box 41. The exceptions are when one species/region can be found in multiple boxes such as 800-0010 - 800-0130 in boxes 88 and 89. The other exceptions are the oversize map case items listed in parenthesis.
      Laboratory of Ornithology number are not arranged by species but CAN be found in the database. In that case, an image with ID Number 2232 would be in Box 101
    - 001-044 (Box 41)
    - 047-058 (Box 42)
    - 060-080 (Box 43)
    - 095-130 (Box 44)
    - 131-132 (Box 45)
    - 133-142 (Box 62)
    - 143-151 (144-0070, 146-0050, 147-0121/22, 148-0020 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 63)
    - 153-166 (156-0100 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 64)
    - 167-178 (173-0030 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 65)
    - 180-191 (Box 66)
    - 194-203 (194-0160 and 194-0180 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 67)
    - 204-224 (204-0031/32 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 68)
    - 225-266 (Box 69)
    - 270- 284 (Box 70)
    - 286-300 (300-0141/42, 300-0151/52 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 71)
    - 301-310 (309-0170, 309-0180, 309-0191/92, 309-0210, 310-0091/92 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 72)
    - 312-332 (Box 73)
    - 333-342 (333-0090, 337-0130 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 74)
    - 343-352 (349-0301/02, 352-0050 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 75)
    - 354-362 (354-0160, 356-0190 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 76)
    - 364-372 (370-0020 in Mapcase - see below) (Box 77)
    - 373-390 (Box 78)
    - 393-412 (Box 79)
    - 416-452 (Box 80)
    - 456-484 (Box 81)
    - 486-501 (Box 82)
    - 503-528 (Box 83)
    - 529-563 (581-0020 is matted with 562-0010) (Box 84)
    - 567-608 (581-0020 in box 84) (Box 85)
    - 612-705 (Box 86)
    - 715-790 (Box 87)
    - 800-0010 - 800-0130 (Box 88)
    - 800-0141 - 800-0750 (Box 89)
    - 810-820 (Box 90)
    - 830-860 (Box 91)
    - 900-0010 - 900-0320 (Box 92)
    - 900-0331 - 900-0790 (Box 93)
    - 900-0800 - 900-1290, Ornithology: 2349, 2350 (Box 94)
    - 900-1300 - 920-0030 (Box 95)
    - 920-0040 - 920-0290 (Box 96)
    - 920-0300 - 920-0660 (Box 97)
    - 147-0121, 147-0122, 148-0020, 156-0100 (Map-case Folder 9)
    - 144-0070 and 146-0050 (Map-case Folder 10)
    - 194-0160 (Map-case Folder 11)
    - 310-0091 and 310-0092 (Map-case Folder 12)
    - 337-0130 (Map-case Folder 13)
    - 352-0050 (Map-case Folder 14)
    - 354-0160 and 356-0190 (Map-case Folder 15)
    - 173-0030 (Map-case Folder 16)
    - 204-0031 and 204-0032 (Map-case Folder 17)
    - 300-0141, 300-0142, 300-0151, 300-0152 (Map-case Folder 18)
    - 309-0170, 309-0180, 309-0191, 309-0192, 309-0210 (Map-case Folder 19)
    - 333-0090 (Map-case Folder 20)
    - 349-0301 and 349-0302 (Map-case Folder 21)
    - 370-0020 (Map-case Folder 22)
    - 194-0080 (Map-case Folder 23)
  - Arranged by Ornithology Numbers (Includes Citizen Bird)
    - Ornithology: 2238, 2250, 2253, 2259, 2260, 2263 (Box 98)
    - Ornithology: 2203, 2220, 2240, 2255, 2257, 2258, 2262 (Box 99)
    - Ornithology: 2239, 2254, 2264, 2280, 2295, 2298, 2313, 5206, 5208 (Box 100)
    - Ornithology: 2232, 2233, 2235, 2244, 2261, 2292, 6202, 6208, 6221-A (Box 101)
    - Ornithology: 2210, 2223, 2231, 2237, 2245, 2294, 5211, 5213 (Box 102)
    - Ornithology: 2206, 2207, 2208, 2230, 2236, 2249 (Box 103)
    - Ornithology: 2251, 2282, 2289, 2290, 2291, 2317, 2342, 2344, 5001 (Box 104)
    - Ornithology: 5202, 5207, 5210, 5212, 5217, 5221-A, 5231, 5233, 5234 (Box 105)
    - Ornithology: 2222, 5253-A, 5253-B, 5253-C, 6210, 6213, 6216, 6222, 6237 (Box 106)
    - Ornithology: 1224, 2226, 2234, 2266 (Box 107)
    - Ornithology: 2287, 2288, 2299, 2316, 5215, 6227 (Box 108)
    - Ornithology: 1, 2, 3, 2201, 2202, 2297, 2300, 2302, 2303, 2304, 2305, 6238, 6117, Whip-poor-will, unnumbered (Box 109)
    - Ornithology: 2340, 2341, 2343, 5203, 5204, 5209, 5214, 5218, 5226, 5230, 5260, 5261, 5262, 5263, 5264, 5265, 5266, 5267, 5268, 5269, 5270, 5271, 5272 (Box 110)
    - Ornithology: 6200-A, 6200-B, 6201-A, 6201-B, 6203, 6204, 6211, 6212, 6214, 6215, 6218, 6219, 6220, 6221-B, 6223, 6224, 6226, 6236 (Box 111)
    - Ornithology: 2786, 2286, 2252, 2293, 2284, 2314, 2204, 2304, 2221, 2315, 6207, 2791 (framed). (Box 118)
    - Ornithology: 2215, 2782, 2789, 2274, 2217, 2277, 2218, 2276, 2216, 2275, 2205 (Box 119)
    - Ornithology: 2783, 2788, 2268, 2785, 2265, 2787, 2279, 2285, 2271, 2228, Pileated woodpecker print (Box 120)
    - Ornithology: 2214, 2267, 2273, 2770 (Map-case Framed Items)
    - Ornithology: 2246, 2296, 5220 (Map-case Folder 6)
    - Ornithology: 5216, 5221, 5222, 5229 (Map-case Folder 7)
    - Ornithology: 2247, 2248, 5205 (Map-case Folder 8)
    - Ornithology: Citizen Bird gouaches: Mallard, Pied-billed Grebe, White-breasted Nuthatch, White-throated Sparrow, Black Duck, Snowy Owl, Rose-breasted Grosbeak, Green-winged Teal, Song Sparrow, Black and White Warbler, Hooded Merganser, Ruddy Turnstone, Black-capped Chickadee, Tree Swallow, Spotted Sandpiper, Eastern Wood-Pewee. (Box 121)
    - Ornithology: Citizen Bird gouaches: Cowbird, Brown Creeper, Yellow-rumped Warbler, Grosbeak, Oldsquaw, Hermit Thrush, American Woodcock, Red-eyed Vireo, Golden Plover. (Box 122)
    - Ornithology: Citizen Bird gouaches: Wilson's Snipe, Common Tern, Least Sandpiper, Bank Swallow, Brown Thrasher, Baltimore Oriole, Snow Bunting, Eastern Kingbird, Wood Duck, Marsh Wren, Ovenbird, Northern Yellowthroat. (Box 123)
  - Artwork Not Found in Database
    - Ornithology: Christmas cards (#8205), Pencil sketch of bear (#5227), Archaeopteryx sketch and humorous poem, n.d. (#5219), Signed mounted published sketch of White or Arctic fox and Pribilof Blue fox (#2346) (Box 116)
    - Ornithology: Kadiak Pine Grosbeak (2037?) - Color Print, 1899 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - Ornithology: Long-tailed Jaeger - Black and white print (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Ornithology: Night-hawk and Whip-poor-will - Color Print (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Ornithology: Booklet: Dogs by Louis Agassiz Fuertes - First Proof, Beck Engraving Company, 1918, article from Nature and Science for Young Folks, with illustrations by Fuertes (2377) (Box 124)
    - Ornithology: Church and Dwight baking soda card originals, 30-1, 30-2, 30-3, 30-5, 30-6, 30-7 x2, 30-8, 30-10, 30-11, 30-13, 30-14, 30-15, 30-16, 30-17, 30-18, 30-19, 30-20, 30-21, 30-22, 30-23, 30-24, 30-25, 30-26, 30-27, 30-28, 30-29, 30-30 (Box 125)
    - Ornithology: 2209 Sunfish, 2359, 2360, 2790, 6225, 2374 2375, 2376, 2378; Christmas cards: 2380, 2381, 2382, 2383, 2384, 2385, 2386, 2387, 2388; Self portrait: 2379; Trail signs: 6228, 6229, 6230, 6231, 6232, 6233, 6234, 6235; Sketchbooks, some from Europe trip: 8202, 8203, 8204; 2 negatives (1 glass, 1 plastic) of a lion made of snow by Fuertes. (Box 126)
    - Ornithology: Test print run pages of illustrations for Birds of New York. (Box 127)
    - Ornithology: March wren drawing and frame (Box 128)
    - RMC: Pencil drawings of animals by Fuertes with color copies of final printed illustrations. (Map-case Folder 25)